<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>focuswriter.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
  <name>FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="af_ZA">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="bs">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="da">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="el">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="en_GB">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="eo">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="es_MX">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="he">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="hu">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="hy">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="ig">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="ja">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">포커스 라이터</name>
  <name xml:lang="lt">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt_BR">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="ro">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="sr">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="vi">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh_CN">FocusWriter</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh_TW">焦點作家</name>
  <summary>Fullscreen word processor</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="af_ZA">Volskerm woordverwerker</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="bs">Aplikacija za rad s tekstom na punom ekranu</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Textový procesor v režimu na celou obrazovku</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="da">Tekstbehandling i fuldskærm</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Vollbild-Textverarbeitungsprogramm</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="el">Επεξεργαστής κειμένου σε πλήρης οθόνη</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eo">Plenekrana tekstoprilaborilo</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Procesador de texto a pantalla completa</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es_MX">Procesador de palabras en pantalla completa</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Koko näytön tekstinkäsittelyohjelma</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Traitement de texte plein écran</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Procesador de texto a pantalla completa</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="he">מעבד תמלילים במסך מלא</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hy">Լիէկրան տեքստային խմբագրիչ</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Layar Penuh</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Un semplice elaboratore di testi a schermo intero</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ja">フルスクリーン・ワードプロセッサ</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">풀스크린 워드 프로세서</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="lt">Viso ekrano žodžių doroklė</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Schermvullende tekstverwerker</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Pełnoekranowy edytor tekstu</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Processador de texto em ecrã completo</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt_BR">Processador de texto em tela cheia</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ro">Procesor de text pe tot ecranul</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">Полноэкранный текстовый редактор</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Celoobrazovkový textový editor</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Polnozaslonski program za pisanje</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sr">Обрађивач текста у пуном екрану</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Ordbehandlare med helskärmsläge</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Tam ekran kelime işlemci</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Повноекранний текстовий редактор</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh_CN">全屏文字编辑器</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh_TW">全螢幕的文字處理器</summary>

  <description>
    <p>FocusWriter is a simple, distraction-free word processor. It utilizes a hide-away interface that you access by moving your mouse to the edges of the screen, allowing the program to have a familiar look and feel to it while still getting out of the way so that you can immerse yourself in your work.</p>
    <p xml:lang="af_ZA">FocusWriter is 'n eenvoudige woordverwerker sonder enige afleidings. Dit maak gebruik van 'n wegsteek-koppelvlak wat jy kan gebruik deur jou muis na die kante van die skerm te beweeg en verskaf sodoende 'n bekende en gebruiklike voorkoms en gevoel, terwyl die program uit jou pad bly dat jy jou in jou werk kan verdiep. </p>
    <p xml:lang="bs">FocusWriter je jednostavan program za rad s tekstom, bez distrakcija. Svi elementi aplikacije skriveni su iz vidokruga i pristupa im se povlačenjem kursora miša do ivica ekrana. Ovakav metod rada kreira radno okruženje na koje se lahko naviknuti i omogućava Vam potpunu koncentraciju na tekst.</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">FocusWriter je jednoduchý, nerozptylující zpracovatel textu. Používá schovávající se rozhraní, ke kterému se dostanete pohybem ukazovátka vaší myši k okrajům obrazovky, čímž programu umožňuje mít důvěrně známý vzhled a dojem z něj, a přitom být z dohledu, takže se můžete ponořit do své práce.</p>
    <p xml:lang="da">FocusWriter er en enkel tekstbehandler fri for distraherende elementer. Den anvender en brugerflade, der gemmes under arbejde med kan fremkaldes ved at føre musen til skærmens kanter, så programmet kan opsættes med kendte redskaber, men på en måde, hvor du kan fordybe dig i dit arbejde.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">FocusWriter ist ein einfaches, ablenkungsfreies Textverarbeitungsprogramm. Die Bedienoberfläche ist nur dann sichtbar, wenn man den Mauszeiger an den Rand des Bildschirms bewegt. Auf dieses Weise lässt sich das Programm intuitiv benutzen, ohne dass die Programmoberfläche ihnen die Sicht auf das versperrt, was eigentlich zählt: Ihre Arbeit.</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Το FocusWriter είναι ένα απλό, χωρίς περισπασμούς πρόγραμμα επεξεργασίας κειμένου. Χρησιμοποιεί μια κρυφή διεπαφή που μπορείτε να αποκτήσετε πρόσβαση μετακινώντας το ποντίκι σας προς τα άκρα της οθόνης, επιτρέποντας στο πρόγραμμα να έχει μια οικεία εμφάνιση και αίσθηση σε αυτόενώ εξακολουθεί να πάρει έξω από το δρόμο, έτσι ώστε να μπορείτε να αφεθείτε στην εργασία σας.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">FocusWriter estas simpla senmalatentiga tekstoprilaborilo. Ĝi uzas kaŝatan interfacon, kion vi atingas per movi vian muson al la randoj de la ekrano. Tiel la programaro eblas havi kutiman fasadon, dum ankoraŭ estas malobstrukciĝante por ke vi povas ĉirkaŭi vin en via laboro.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">FocusWriter es un procesador de texto simple y libre de distracciones. Utiliza una interfaz que se esconde automáticamente y a la que puedes acceder moviendo el ratón hacia las esquinas de la pantalla, dando al programa esa sensación de familiaridad mientras se mantiene fuera de tu camino, para que puedas concentrarte en tú trabajo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es_MX">FocusWriter es un procesador de palabras simple y sin distractores. Éste utiliza una interfaz aislada que puede ser accedida moviendo el ratón a las esquinas de la pantalla, permitiendo que el programa tener una apariencia similar a cuando uno se aparta de todo y se puede concentrar sólo en su trabajo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">FocusWriter on yksinkertainen ja häiriötekijätön tekstinkäsittelyohjelma. Siinä on automaattisesti piiloutuva käyttöliittymä, johon pääsee siirtämällä hiiren näytön laitoihin. Sen ansiosta ohjelmassa on tuttu ulkoasu ja käyttötuntuma. Samalla käyttöliittymä väistyy työhön uppoutumisen tieltä.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">FocusWriter est un traitement de texte simple et non intrusif. Il utilise une interface masquée, accessible en déplaçant votre souris vers les coins de l'écran, ce qui confère au programme un aspect convivial tout en restant discret afin que vous puissiez vous plonger dans votre travail.</p>
    <p xml:lang="he">‏FocusWriter הינו מעבד תמלילים פשוט, נטול הפרעה. זה מנצל ממשק מחבוא (hide-away) אשר אליו ניגשים בעזרת הזזת עכבר על קצות המסך, מה שמתיר לתוכנית לקבל מראה ותחושה מוכרים בעוד שזה עדיין נותר באין מפריע כך שהתהא באפשרותך להשקיע את עצמך לתוך עבודתך.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hy">FocusWriter-ն արտաքին շեղումներից ուշադրությունը զերծ պահող պարզ տեքստային խմբագրիչ է։ Այն գործածում է թաքնվող միջերես, որը հասանելի է դառնում էկրանի ծայրերին մկնիկի շարժմամբ հպվելու միջոցով։ Սա թե՛ ծրագրին տալիս է գործածողի աչքի համար սովորական տեսք ու զգացողություն, թե՛ միաժամանակ նրան թույլ տալիս խորասուզվել աշխատանքի մեջ, առանց ուշադրությունն արտաքին հանգամանքներով շեղելու։</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">FocusWriter merupakan pengolah kata yang bebas pengalihan dan sederhana. Menggunakan antarmuka yang Anda akses dengan cara menggerakkan mouse ke tepi layar, membuat program ini memilik tampilan yang familiar dan memudahkan Anda untuk menyelam ke dalam pekerjaan Anda.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">FocusWriter è un elaboratore di testi semplice e senza distrazioni. Impiega un'interfaccia nascosta accessibile muovendo il puntatore del mouse ai lati dello schermo, dando al programma un aspetto familiare, rimanendo semplice e pulito, in modo che tu possa immergerti completamente nel tuo lavoro.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ja">FocusWriter はシンプルなディストラクション・フリーのワード・プロセッサーです。普段は隠されているインターフェイスにはマウスを画面端に動かすだけでアクセスできるようになっているので、プログラムの基本的なルック・アンド・フィールは維持したまま、作業に没頭することができるでしょう。</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">포커스 라이터는, 글쓰기에 집중하게 해주는 간단한 워드 프로세서입니다. 마우스를 화면 끝에 대면 작동하는 하이드-어웨이 방식을 적용해서, 프로그램이 익숙한 모양과 느낌을 유지하게 해, 잠시 방해를 받아도 금방 하던 작업에 몰두하게 합니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="lt">FocusWriter yra paprasta žodžių doroklė be išblaškymų. Ji naudoja besislepiančią sąsają, kurią galima pasiekti, nuvedant pelės žymeklį prie ekrano ribų. Ši sąsaja suteikia programai pažįstamą išvaizdą ir jausmą, todėl programa jums netrukdo, o jūs galite pilnai pasinerti į savo darbą.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Focuswriter is een eenvoudige, afleidingsvrije tekstverwerker. Het verbergt de gebruikersomgeving totdat de cursor naar de rand van het scherm wordt geschoven. De applicatie heeft de bekende uitstraling maar stelt je tevens in staat om je volledig te focussen op je werk.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">FocusWriter to prosty, pełnoekranowy edytor tekstu. Korzysta z ukrytego interfejsu, do którego otrzymujesz dostęp przesuwając kursor myszkę do krawędzi ekranu. W ten sposób program skupia twoją uwagę na to, co naprawdę jest najważniejsze: twoja praca.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O FocusWriter é um processador de texto simples e sem distrações. A interface só aparece quando o cursor se aproxima das margens do ecrã, proporcionando um aspeto familiar que ao mesmo tempo não ocupa espaço e lhe permite focar-se no seu trabalho.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt_BR">FocusWriter é um processador de texto simples livre de distrações. Ele utiliza uma interface oculta, acessível ao mover o mouse para os cantos da tela, o que dá ao programa um visual familiar, mas discreto. Assim você pode mergulhar em seu trabalho.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ro">FocusWriter este un procesor de text simplu, fără distragerea atenţiei. Acesta folosește o interfaţă ascunsă pe care o accesaţi prin mutarea mouse-ului pe marginile ecranului, care permite programului să aibă un aspect şi un simţămînt familiar în timp ce se dă la o parte, astfel încît să vă puteţi cufunda în munca dvs.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">FocusWriter - это простой текстовый редактор, позволяющий полностью сосредоточиться на работе. В нем используется выдвижной интерфейс, управляющие элементы которого становятся доступными при наведении стрелки мыши к краям экрана. Это дает возможность добиться максимально располагающего к пользователю внешнего вида и полностью погрузиться в вашу работу.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">FocusWriter je jednoduchý textový editor bez rozptýlení. Využíva skryté rozhranie, ku ktorému sa pristupuje pohybom myši na okraje obrazovky, čo umožňuje programu mať prirodzený vzhľad a dojem, zatiaľ čo si stále udržujete odstup, takže sa môžete ponoriť do svojej práce.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">FocusWriter je enostaven urejevalnik besedil. Uporablja skrit uporabniški vmesnik do katerega dostopamo tako, da miško pomaknemo ob rob zaslona, kar omogoča, da ima program domač/znan izgled, medtem, ko omogoča nemoteno delo in se lahko pisanju popolnoma posvetimo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr">FocusWriter је једноставан, слободан уређивач текста. Он користи скривени интерфејс коме се приступа померањем миша на ивице екрана, омогућавајући програму да добије познати изглед и тако вам обезбеди да се посветите вашем раду.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">FocusWriter är en enkel, distraktionsfri ordbehandlare. Den utnyttjar ett dolt gränssnitt som du kommer åt genom att flytta din mus till skärmkanterna, vilket tillåter programmet att ha välbekant utseende och känsla, medan det håller sig ur vägen så att du kan fördjupa dig i ditt arbete. </p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">FocusWriter це простий текстовий редактор, що дозволяє повністю зосередитися на роботі. Він використовує висувний інтерфейс, який з’являється при наведенні стрілки миші до країв екрану. Це дає можливість досягти максимально зручного для користувача зовнішнього вигляду, який не відволікає, а дозволяє повністю зануритися в роботу.</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_CN">FocusWriter 是个简洁的，让您专心于写作的文字编辑器。所有菜单默认隐藏，当鼠标滑动到屏幕边缘时会显示。这样既提供所需功能，又能保证让您专注于写作。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_TW">「焦點作家」是一個簡潔、讓您不受干擾的文字處理器。除了寫作區域以外，其他介面均在您將滑鼠移到螢幕邊緣時才會顯示，這樣既能提供所需的功能，又能讓您專心寫作。</p>
    <p>FocusWriter allows you to customize your environment by creating themes that control the font, colors, and background image to add ambiance. It also features on-the-fly updating statistics, daily goals, multiple open documents, spell-checking, and much more.</p>
    <p xml:lang="af_ZA">FocusWriter laat jou toe om jou omgewing te verpersoonlik. Jy kan tema's gebruik wat die lettertipe, kleure, en agtergrondfoto verander om 'n eie atmosfeer te skep. Die program ondersteun statistiek wat deurlopend opdateer, daaglikse doelwitte, veelvoudige oop dokumente, speltoetsing, en vele meer.</p>
    <p xml:lang="bs">FocusWriter omogućava Vam da prilagodite radni ambijent vlastitom ukusu kreirajući teme koje sadržavaju različite fontove, boje i pozadinske slike. Aplikacija nudi i statistiku o tekstu, definisanje dnevnih ciljeva, otvaranje više dokumenata u isto vrijeme, provjeru pravopisa i brojne druge mogućnosti.</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">FocusWriter vám umožňuje si své prostředí přizpůsobit vytvořením vzhledů, jež řídí písmo, barvy, a obrázek na pozadí, čímž se pracovnímu prostředí přidá určitá nálada. Nabízí také za běhu se obnovující statistikou, denní cíle, možnost mít více otevřených dokumentů, ověřování pravopisu, a mnohé další.</p>
    <p xml:lang="da">FocusWriter kan tilpasse arbejdsmiljøet ved at arbejde med temaer, der kontrollerer skrifttype, farver og et baggrundsbillede for stemning. Programmet har også statistik, der opdateres mens du arbejder, daglige mål, mulighed for flere åbne dokumenter, stavekontrol og meget andet.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">FocusWriter erlaubt es Ihnen, die Benutzeroberfläche anzupassen. indem Sie mittel selbst erstellter Themen die Schriftart, Farben und das Hintergrundbild des Programms einstellen, schaffen Sie ihre eigene Arbeitsatmosphäre. Weitere Bestandteile sind Echtzeit-Statistiken, Tagesziele, das Öffnen mehrerer Dokumente gleichzeitig, Rechtschreibkorrektur und vieles mehr.</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Το FocusWriter σας επιτρέπει να προσαρμόσετε το περιβάλλον σας, δημιουργώντας θέματα που ελέγχουν την γραμματοσειρά, τα χρώματα και το φόντο της εικόνας για να προσθέσετε ατμόσφαιρα. Διαθέτει επίσης on-the-fly στατιστικές ενημέρωσης, καθημερινούς στόχους, πολλά ανοικτά έγγραφα, ορθογραφικό έλεγχο, και πολλά άλλα.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">FocusWriter ebligas vin agordi vian verkejon per kreado de etosoj, kiuj agordas la tiparon, kolorojn, kaj fonan bildon por ŝanĝi etoson. Ĝi ankaŭ havas funkciojn por tuje ĝisdatiganta statistiko, ĉiutagaj celoj, plure da malfermataj dokumentoj, literumada kontrolo, kaj multe pli.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">FocusWriter te permite personalizar el entorno creando temas que controlan la fuente, los colores y la imagen de fondo para crear ambiente. También incorpora estadísticas de escritura, objetivos diarios, apertura de múltiples documentos, comprobación de ortografía y mucho mas.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es_MX">FocusWriter permite personalizar su ambiente creado temas que controlan la fuente, los colores y la imagen de fondo para crear un ambiente. Otras características son que actualiza en tiempo real estadísticas, metas diarias, abre múltiples documentos, verifica ortografía y mucho más.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">FocusWriterin ympäristöä voi muokata luomaan tunnelmaa tekemällä teemoja, jotka vaihtavat fontit, värit ja taustakuvan. FocusWriterissa on myös automaattisesti päivittyvät tilastot, päivittäiset tavoitteet, tuki useille avoimille tiedostoille, oikeinkirjoituksen tarkistus ja paljon muuta.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">FocusWriter vous permet de personnaliser votre environnement en créant des thèmes composés de polices, de couleurs et d'images d'arrière-plan afin d'agrémenter votre interface. Il inclut également des statistiques mises à jour à la volée, des objectifs quotidiens, l'ouverture de documents multiples, une vérification orthographique, et bien plus encore.</p>
    <p xml:lang="he">‏FocusWriter מאפשר לך להתאים את סביבתך על ידי יצירת ערכות נושא אשר שולטות על הגופן, הצבעים ועל תמונת הרקע כדי להוסיף אווירה. זה גם טומן בחובו עדכון סטטיסטיקה, יעדים יומיים, פתיחה מרובה של מסמכים, בדיקת-איות, ועוד הרבה יותר.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hy">FocusWriter-ը գործածողին թույլ է տալիս ստեղծել աշխատանքի սեփական միջավայր՝ թեմաների միջոցով, որոնցով կարելի է ընտրել տառատեսակը, գույները և որևէ նկարով խորապատկեր՝ որոշակի տրամադրություն ստեղծելու համար։ Այն նաև ցույց է տալիս մուտքագրվող նյութի մանրամասն վիճակագրությունը, թույլ տալիս սահմանել աշխատանքի օրական սահմանաքանակ, հնարավորություն ունի մեկ պատուհանում միանգամից շատ նիշքեր բացելու, ուղղագրությունը ստուգելու և այլն։</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">FocusWriter membuat Anda untuk menciptakan lingkungan Anda sendiri dengan cara membuat tema yang mengatur jenis huruf, warna, dan gambar latar untuk menambah suasana. Program ini juga dilengkapi oleh statistika yang selalu diperbarui setiap saat, tujuan sehari-hari, membuka banyak dokumen sekaligus, pengecekan ejaan, dan masih banyak lagi.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">FocusWriter ti consente di personalizzare il tuo ambiente di lavoro attraverso la creazione ti temi con carattere, colori, e immagine di sfondo scelti da te, creando un'atmosfera personale per immergerti nel tuo lavoro. Il programma include anche statistiche in tempo reale, obiettivi giornalieri, più documenti aperti contemporaneamente, controllo ortografico, e molto altro.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ja">FocusWriter ではフォント・色・背景画像などテーマとして作り、それを使って作業環境をカスタマイズすることができます。またリアルタイムな文書の統計情報の表示、進捗管理、複数文書の編集、スペル・チェッカーなどといった機能もあります。</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">포커스 라이터는 폰트와, 색상을 조절하고, 배경 그림을 추가해 테마를 만들어서 작업 환경을 직접 만들 수 있게 되어있습니다. 포커스 라이터는 때에 따라서 이용할 수 있는 통계 업데이트, 오늘의 목표, 여러 건의 문서 열기, 맞춤법 검사, 등과 그 외에 아주 많은 기능을 갖고 있습니다.  </p>
    <p xml:lang="lt">FocusWriter leidžia jums tinkinti savo aplinką, kuriant temas, kurios kontroliuoja šriftą, spalvas ir fono paveikslą bei sukuria norimą atmosferą. Programoje yra statistikos atnaujinimo, kasdienio tikslo, kelių atvertų dokumentų, rašybos tikrinimo ir daugybė kitų funkcijų.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Focuswriter stelt je in staat om de applicatie aan te passen aan de wensen van lettertype, kleuren en achtergrondafbeeldingen om de gewenste sfeer te creëren. Het beschikt ook over direct bijgewerkte statistieken, dagelijkse doelen, meerdere geopende documenten, spellingcorrectie en nog veel meer.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">FocusWriter umożliwia dostosowanie wyglądu poprzez tworzenie motywów, które ustawiają czcionkę, kolory i obraz tła, aby stworzyć własną atmosferę. Posiada również aktualizację statystyk w locie, codzienne cele, otwieranie wielu dokumentów jednocześnie, sprawdzanie pisowni i dużo więcej.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O FocusWriter permite-lhe personalizar o ambiente de trabalho com a criação de temas, controlando a fonte tipográfica, cores e imagem de fundo. Também dispõe de estatísticas atualizadas, objetivos diários, vários documentos abertos ao mesmo tempo, verificação ortográfica e muito mais.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt_BR">FocusWriter permite que você personalize o seu ambiente, criando temas que possibilitam a mudança da fonte, cores e imagem de fundo, para criar a atmosfera ideal. Também permite atualização de estatísticas, metas diárias, vários documentos abertos, verificação ortográfica e muito mais.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ro">FocusWriter vă permite să personalizaţi mediul prin crearea de teme care controlează font-ul, culorile şi imaginea de fundal pentru a adăuga ambianţă. Acesta oferă, de asemenea, statistici de actualizare, obiective de zi cu zi, mai multe documente deschise, verificare ortografică, şi mult mai mult.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">FocusWriter позволит вам настроить свое рабочее окружение путем создания тем, в которых можно,  для добавления нужной атмосферы, управлять шрифтами, цветами и фоновыми изображениями. Также текстовый редактор умеет вести статистику, обновляемую в реальном времени, ставить ежедневные рабочие цели, открывать сразу несколько документов одновременно, проверять орфографию и много чего еще.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">FocusWriter umožňuje prispôsobiť vaše prostredie vytvorením tém, ktoré ovládajú písmo, farby a obrázok na pozadí na pridanie atmosféry. Je tiež vybavený funkciami ako priebežná aktualizácia štatistík, denné ciele, viac otvorených dokumentov, kontrolu pravopisu a oveľa viac.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">FocusWriter omogoča prilagajanje okolja z uporabo tem, ki omogočajo nadzor pisav, barv in slike za ozadje urejevalnika. Omogoča tudi takojšnjo statistiko, dnevne cilje, več odprtih dokumentov, preverjanje pravopisa in še veliko več.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr">FocusWriter вам омогућава да прилагодите окружење креирањем теме са фонтом, бојама и позадинском сликом. Такође, поседује ажурирање статистике, дневне циљеве, истовремено отварање више докумената, проверу правописа и још много тога.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">FocusWriter tillåter dig att anpassa din miljö genom att skapa teman som kontrollerar typsnitt, färger, och bakgrundsbilden för att lägga till atmosfär. Den har även automatisk statistikuppdatering, dagliga mål, flera öppna dokument, stavningskontroll och mycket mer.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">FocusWriter дозволить вам налаштувати своє робоче оточення шляхом створення тем, в яких можна управляти шрифтами, кольорами та фоновими зображеннями. Також текстовий редактор вміє вести статистику, оновлювану в реальному часі, ставити щоденні робочі цілі, відкривати декілька документів одночасно, перевіряти орфографію і багато чого ще.</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_CN">FocusWriter 支持自定义主题，可以调整字体，颜色，背景图像等。还有很多其他功能，如动态更新统计，每日计划，多标签页，拼写检查等。</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_TW">「焦點作家」可以自訂主題、更改字體、顏色、以及背景圖片等等。也有如動態更新統計；每日目標、多重開啟文件、拼字校正等等的多種功能。</p>
    <p>Additionally, when you open the program your current work in progress will automatically load and position you where you last left off so that you can immediately jump back in.</p>
    <p xml:lang="af_ZA">Voorts laai die program die dokument waarmee jy besig was, asook presies waar in die dokument jy besig was, wanneer jy die program oopmaak. So kan jy dadelik aan die werk spring.</p>
    <p xml:lang="bs">Kada otvorite program, svi dokumenti na kojima trenutno radite bit će automatski učitani, a kursor će u svakom od njih biti na istoj poziciji na kojoj se nalazio kada ste zadnji put zatvorili dokument. To Vam omogućava da odmah nastavite s radom tačno ondje gdje ste zadnji put stali.</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">Navíc, když otevřete program, vaše rozdělaná práce se automaticky nahraje a otevře se na místě, kde jste ji naposledy opustily, takže se do ní zase budete moci okamžitě dát.</p>
    <p xml:lang="da">Desuden gemmes og genåbnes dit arbejde automatisk, så programmet ved opstart vil indlæse det seneste dokument og placere markøren hvor den var, så du med det samme kan komme tilbage i teksten.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Darüberhinaus lädt das Programm beim Start automatisch ihr zuletzt geöffnetes Dokument an der Stelle, an der Sie zuletzt gearbeitet haben, sodass Sie ihre Arbeit direkt fortsetzen können.</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Επιπλέον, όταν ανοίγετε στο πρόγραμμα την τρέχουσα εργασία σας θα φορτώσει αυτόματα και την θέση όπου σταματήσατε, έτσι ώστε να μπορείτε να μεταβείτε αμέσως πίσω.</p>
    <p xml:lang="eo">Plue, kiam vi lanĉas la programaron, via lasta malpreta verko aŭtomate ŝarĝas kaj allokas vin, kie vi laste ĉesis, por ke vi povas daŭri verki tuj.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Además, cuando abres el programa se cargará automáticamente tu trabajo actual y la posición donde lo dejaste, de forma que puedas continuar inmediatamente con él.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es_MX">Además, cuando se abre el programa, su trabajo actual se cargará y la posición en la que dejó la última vez para que pueda continuar inmediatamente.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Lisäksi ohjelman käynnistyessä kesken jäänyt työ ladataan automaattisesti siltä kohtaa, mihin viimeksi jäit, jotta työn jatkaminen on helppoa.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">De plus, lorsque vous lancez le programme, votre travail en cours sera automatiquement chargé et vous vous retrouverez là où vous vous étiez arrêté, de sorte que vous puissiez immédiament vous remettre à l'ouvrage.</p>
    <p xml:lang="he">נוסף על כך, כאשר תפתח את התוכנית העבודה שלך אשר מצויה בתהליך תיטען מחדש וימקם אותך היכן שנותרת בפעם אחרונה בה עזבת כך שתהא באפשרותך לקפוץ בחזרה מיידית.</p>
    <p xml:lang="hy">Բացի դրանից, ծրագիրը բացվելիս լռելյայն ցուցադրում է այն վերջին նիշքը, որի վրա գործածողն աշխատել է, և հենց այն հատվածում, որում նա վերջին անգամ փոփոխություն է կատարել, ինչը հնարավորություն է տալիս շարունակելու աշխատանքն այնտեղից, որտեղ այն վերջին անգամ ընդհատվել էր։</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Ditambah lagi, ketika Anda membuka program, pekerjaan Anda yang sedang dikerjaan akan otomatis dimuat dan memulai di mana Anda terakhir meninggalkannya sehingga Anda bisa memulainya lagi lebih cepat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Inoltre, quando apri il programma il tuo lavoro in corso d'opera si apre automaticamente nella posizione in cui l'avevi lasciato, in modo che possa riprendere immediatamente a lavorarci.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ja">更には、現在のプロジェクトをプログラム開くと、以前の作業状況がカーソル位置も含め復元されるので、直ぐに続きを書き始めることが出来ます。</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">그리고, 프로그램을 열면 작업하던 내용이 일을 멈추고 떠났던 그때 그대로 자동으로 복귀되어서 돌아오면 바로 하던 작업으로 다시 돌아갈 수 있습니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="lt">Be to, kai atidarote programą, jūsų dabartinis darbas yra automatiškai įkeliamas toje vietoje, kurioje paskutinį kartą užbaigėte, todėl nedvejodami galite vėl kibti į darbą.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Daarnaast laadt de applicatie, na het opstarten, automatisch je huidige werk op de laatst bekende locatie zodat je direct verder kunt.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Ponadto, program automatycznie ładuje przy starcie ostatni otworzony dokument i pozycję, na której ostatnio przerwano, aby można od razu kontynuować pracę.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Além disto, o programa abre automaticamente o trabalho em curso e posiciona o cursor na posição em que se encontrava na sessão anterior, para que possa voltar ao trabalho sem demoras.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt_BR">Além disso, quando você abrir o programa, seu trabalho em andamento será automaticamente carregado e posicionado onde você parou, de modo que você pode reiniciá-lo imediatamente.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ro">În plus, atunci când deschideţi programul, lucrul dvs. în curs de execuţie va fi încărcat automat şi poziția unde aţi rămas ultima dată, astfel încît să puteţi trece imediat la treabă.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Кроме того, когда вы откроете программу, сразу же будет загружен прогресс вашей текущей работы и курсор перейдет на ту позицию, на которой в последний раз работа была прервана. Так вы сможете практически мгновенно вернуться к делу.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Navyše, pri otvorení programu sa vaša aktuálne rozpracovaná práca automaticky načíta na pozícii, kde ste naposledy skončili, takže môžete okamžite skočiť naspäť.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Dodatno, ko zaženemo program se bo vaše zadnje delo samodejno naložilo in postavilo delovno mesto na zadnjo znano pozicijo, tako, da lahko takoj nadaljujete kjer ste ostali prejšnjič.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sr">Поред тога, када отворите програм, ваш тренутни посао ће се аутоматски учитати на месту где сте последњи пут стали, тако да га можете одмах наставити.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Dessutom, när du öppnar programmet kommer ditt pågående arbete att laddas automatiskt där du slutade senast så att du omedelbart kan fortsätta</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Крім того, коли ви відкриєте програму, відразу ж буде завантажений прогрес вашої поточної роботи і курсор перейде на ту позицію, на якій в останній раз робота була перервана. Так ви зможете практично миттєво повернутися до справи.</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_CN">另外，打开软件后会自动跳到上次编辑的位置，让您立刻继续投入工作</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh_TW">另外，打開您正在撰寫的文件會自動跳至您最後一次編輯的位置，讓您可以繼續進行工作。</p>
  </description>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://gottcode.org/focuswriter/screenshots/appdata.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://gottcode.org/focuswriter/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://gottcode.org/focuswriter/bugs/</url>
  <url type="donation">https://gottcode.org/tip/</url>
  <url type="translate">https://www.transifex.com/projects/p/focuswriter/</url>

  <developer_name>Graeme Gott</developer_name>
  <update_contact>graeme@gottcode.org</update_contact>

  <translation type="qt">focuswriter</translation>

  <provides>
    <binary>focuswriter</binary>
  </provides>

  <kudos>
    <kudo>HiDpiIcon</kudo>
    <kudo>ModernToolkit</kudo>
  </kudos>

  <releases>
    <release version="1.6.15" date="2018-07-20">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>FIXED: Automatic high DPI support</li>
          <li>Translation updates: Galician, Spanish</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.6.14" date="2018-07-06">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>FIXED: Regression where emergency cache didn't run</li>
          <li>Renamed NEWS to ChangeLog</li>
          <li>Translation updates: Bosnian</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.6.13" date="2018-05-29">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Updated dictionaries</li>
          <li>Updated Unicode symbols database</li>
          <li>Replaced deprecated code</li>
          <li>Extra warnings only shown in debug build</li>
          <li>Improved Linux deployment</li>
          <li>Improved macOS deployment</li>
          <li>Improved Windows deployment</li>
          <li>Translation updates: Dutch, French, Portuguese</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
